<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on Dominic Motuka</title>
    <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on Dominic Motuka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 17:44:28 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dominicmotuka.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Docker Commands</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/useful-docker-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 17:44:28 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/useful-docker-commands/</guid>
      <description>Docker commands you should know Automatically start containers - restart policies   Restart policies to control whether your containers start automatically when they exit, or when Docker restart
  Restart policies ensure that linked containers are started in the correct order.
  Docker recommends that you use restart policies, and avoid using process managers to start containers.
  To configure the restart policy for a container, use the &amp;ndash;restart flag when using the docker run command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Docker Machine</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/how-to-docker-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 15:12:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/how-to-docker-machine/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker? Docker is the command-line tool that uses containerization to manage multiple images and containers and volumes and such &amp;ndash; a container is basically a lightweight virtual machine.
Where does docker machine come in? When using a containerized application, it’s important to be able to easily deploy them in the cloud. Docker-Machine is a tool that lets you install Docker Engine on Virtual Hosts.
Since Docker isn&amp;rsquo;t running on your actual host OS, docker-machine needs to deal with IP addresses and ports and volumes and such.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>