<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dominic Motuka</title>
    <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dominic Motuka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 23:37:41 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dominicmotuka.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Associate Cloud Engineer Notes</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/associate-cloud-engineer-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 23:37:41 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/associate-cloud-engineer-notes/</guid>
      <description>Short Notes In Preparation of Google Associate Cloud Engineer Exam Stackdriver ( Monitoring, logging, and debugging. ) Stackdriver metadata is stored in the host project.
Stackdriver was previously a third-party application. When using Stackdriver, you may be transferred between different domains.
A good project ID describes the project and environment e.g bench-projects-production
When creating a new account, choose the payments profile to pay for a Google Play developer license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Virtualbox Guest Additions Centos8</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/installing-virtualbox-guest-additions-centos8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 12:35:18 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/installing-virtualbox-guest-additions-centos8/</guid>
      <description>From tecmint ; VirtualBox Guest Additions are a collection of device drivers and system applications designed to achieve closer integration between the host and guest operating systems. They help to enhance the overall interactive performance and usability of guest systems.
The VirtualBox Guest Additions offer the following features:
 Easy mouse pointer integration. Easy way to share folders between the host and the guest. Drag and drop feature allows copying or opening files, copy clipboard formats from the host to the guest or from the guest to the host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Stackdriver Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/google-stackdriver-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 12:01:37 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/google-stackdriver-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Stackdriver Monitoring provides visibility into the performance, uptime, and overall health of cloud-powered applications.
Stackdriver collects metrics, events, and metadata from:
 Google Cloud Platform Amazon Web Services Hosted uptime probes Application instrumentation Common application components including Cassandra, Nginx, Apache Web Server, Elasticsearch e.t.c  Stackdriver ingests that data and generates insights via:
 Dashboards Charts And alerts.  Stackdriver alerting helps you collaborate by integrating with Slack, PagerDuty, HipChat, Campfire, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commonly Used Potgres Commands</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/commonly-used-potgres-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:23:09 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/commonly-used-potgres-commands/</guid>
      <description>What is psql psql is the interactive terminal for administering postgre. The most important flags available are:
 h the host to connect to U the user to connect with p the port to connect to (default is 5432)   psql -h localhost -U username databasename
 The other option is to use a string and let psql parse it:
 psql &amp;ldquo;dbname=dbhere host=hosthere user=userhere password=pwhere port=5432 sslmode=require&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dotnet(.NET) CI CD With CircleCI</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/dotnet-ci-cd-with-circleci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:30:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/dotnet-ci-cd-with-circleci/</guid>
      <description>What is .NET sdk .NET Core SDK consists of two parts: the .NET Core runtime and the .NET CLI. The runtime allows you to run .NET Core applications, whereas the CLI tools are a command-line interface that allows you to develop .NET Core applications.
In this blog post, we will build a small .NET Core console application, then, we will use CircleCi to show how continuous Integrations can be setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDump and MongoRestore MongoDB Database</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/mongodump-and-mongorestore-mongodb-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 20:49:18 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/mongodump-and-mongorestore-mongodb-database/</guid>
      <description>How to Dump MongoDB Ddatabase from a container What is mongodump mongodump is a utility for creating a binary export of the contents of a database. mongodump can export data from either mongod or mongos instances.
Run mongodump from the system command line, not the mongo shell.
How to connect to a MongoDB instance  Local MongoDB instance running on port 27017 using the default settings
mongodump By specifying a host and/or port of the MongoDB instance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Docker Machine</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/how-to-docker-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 15:12:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/how-to-docker-machine/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker? Docker is the command-line tool that uses containerization to manage multiple images and containers and volumes and such &amp;ndash; a container is basically a lightweight virtual machine.
Where does docker machine come in? When using a containerized application, it’s important to be able to easily deploy them in the cloud. Docker-Machine is a tool that lets you install Docker Engine on Virtual Hosts.
Since Docker isn&amp;rsquo;t running on your actual host OS, docker-machine needs to deal with IP addresses and ports and volumes and such.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Graphql</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/what-is-graphql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 10:13:21 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/what-is-graphql/</guid>
      <description>GraphQL is a syntax that describes how to ask for data, and is generally used to load data from a server to a client. GraphQL has three main characteristics:
  It lets the client specify exactly what data it needs. It makes it easier to aggregate data from multiple sources. It uses a type system to describe data.  With GraphQL, the user is able to make a single call to fetch the required information rather than to construct several REST requests to fetch the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacOS Setup for Software Development</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/development-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:46:32 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/development-setup/</guid>
      <description>First Things First After first login, run Software Update and ensure that the operating system is at the latest point of release. This will ensure that you have a more secure OS. Also since macOS upgrades are free, you might as well keep your machine up to date.
 To do that go: Apple menu () &amp;gt; About This Mac &amp;gt; Software Update.
 Restart the computer when prompted to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samurai Jack Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/samurai-jack-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:46:26 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/samurai-jack-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Long ago in a distant land, I, Aku, the shape-shifting Master of Darkness, unleashed an unspeakable evil! But a foolish Samurai warrior wielding a magic sword stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck, I tore open a portal in time and flung him into the future, where my evil is law! Now the fool seeks to return to the past, and undo the future that is Aku!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>