<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dominic Motuka</title>
    <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dominic Motuka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:46:39 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dominicmotuka.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Third Post</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/my-third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:46:39 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/my-third-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacOS Setup for Software Development</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/development-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:46:32 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/development-setup/</guid>
      <description>First Things First After first login, run Software Update and ensure that the operating system is at the latest point of release. This will ensure that you have a more secure OS. Also since macOS upgrades are free, you might as well keep your machine up to date.
 To do that go: Apple menu () &amp;gt; About This Mac &amp;gt; Software Update.
 Restart the computer when prompted to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samurai Jack Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/samurai-jack-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:46:26 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/posts/samurai-jack-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Long ago in a distant land, I, Aku, the shape-shifting Master of Darkness, unleashed an unspeakable evil! But a foolish Samurai warrior wielding a magic sword stepped forth to oppose me.
Before the final blow was struck, I tore open a portal in time and flung him into the future, where my evil is law! Now the fool seeks to return to the past, and undo the future that is Aku!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Dominic Motuka</title>
      <link>https://dominicmotuka.com/about-dominic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:45:07 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominicmotuka.com/about-dominic/</guid>
      <description>DevOps Engineer driven by the motivation to help teams achieve a common goal by leveraging technology.
I work in teams to establish automation pipelines, develop scripts to automate development operations, configuration management and provide actionable feedback.
I am a lifelong learner and I continuously seek avenues to improve my knowledge, skills, and capabilities to both strengthen familiar skills and learn new technologies. This means that I work with others to define approaches and execute solutions comprising:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>